A Guide to the Arlington County Public Schools, 1909-2005
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington County Public Schools, 1909-2005
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 7
38 boxes.
Arlington Public Schools (Arlington, Va.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
These unofficial records were gathered from various sources including Warren Cox, a School Board Chair, and Alice Suffit, a teacher in teh Arlington County system. There are numerous other small donations added to this collection over the years - please see specific donor and accession records.
Scope and Content
Record Group 7 contains the incomplete and unofficial records of the Arlington County, Virginia, public school system. The entire collection measures 20.85 linear feet, and ranges in date between 1909 and 2004. The bulk of the material is from the period 1946-1988. Materials include information on School Board candidates, architectural reports and site studies for school buildings, school personnel handbooks, salary and retirement information from the 1950s, reports of citizen advisory councils and task forces on instructional issues (1950s through 1970s) and many school publications including newsletters and clippings about Arlington schools, chiefly during the 1950s through the 1970s.
Subgroup 1: General Records (1909-1995)
This subgroup contains records that refer to the county school system and its policies. Researchers will find information on the School Board nomination process and School Board concerns in the 1950s, school integration, finances, school buildings and population, personnel policies, curriculum changes and developments, citizen concerns as related by advisory councils, approaches to dealing with student problems and publicity concerning the schools. Subgroup 1 contains correspondence and memoranda, publications, budgets, meeting minutes, reports, maps, photographs and clippings. The bulk of the material dates from 1950-1980.
Subgroup 2: Individual Schools (1910-2004)
Subgroup 2 focuses on individual schools, and contains correspondence, memoranda, clippings, publications and programs, reports, photographs, newsletters and some oversized materials. The bulk of the material dates from 1950-1960 and 1970-1985. There are also several CD-ROMs with page captures from Swanson Middle School's website and scans of historical photographs for an anniversary publication. The information in this subgroup concentrates on individual school policies, procedures and special events. There are also many photographs, both of school events and staff and more formal classbooks, which are albums with school portraits of all students, arranged by classroom. Some of these books have photograph identification.
Subgroup 3: Parent-Teacher Associations and Council of PTAs (1916-2004)
Subgroup 3 contains scattered records of numerous Arlington school PTAs, the bulk of which is from 1948-1980. Types of material include bylaws, histories, newspaper clippings, handbooks, minutes, financial documents, newsletters, correspondence, reports, and photographs. While the material in many of these series is sparse, several PTAs have more complete files, such as Cherrydale PTA (1916-1969), Fairlington PTA (1952-1979), Walter Reed PTA (1921-1984), and Woodmont PTA (1935-1982). There was also a central body with representatives from individual school PTAs called the Council of PTAs. They had were part of a similar group for the commonwealth of Virginia. Generally, the records reflect efforts to raise money (through social events and other activities) in order to provide equipment and library books for the schools. The PTAs also promoted health and safety and attractive school surroundings. Several Arlington County public schools have been closed (such as Woodmont), and the records show activities to prevent closings or to ease the transition to a new school.
Arrangement
RG 7 is divided into three subgroups. Because this collection is the product of many separate and distinct donations by various individuals, they have been arranged by subject; one donation can be filed in several different places, according to subject matter. Donations of single documents are added into the appropriate subgroup and series, but new materials are added at the end of a specific series.
When listing dates of material, a hyphen is used to show a range of dates (i.e. 1947-1952). When a hyphen is used, the date refers to a full school year, September to June (i.e. 1947/48). If material specifically refers to a complete school year, such as with handbooks or class photographs, the school year is noted in the date on the folder.
Oversized materials have been removed to proper housing; separation sheets have been placed in the original location. In the Box Listing, files with oversize materials will have an asterisk (*). At the end of this finding there is a short inventory of RG 7 oversize boxes. Sometimes photographs are found within folders of paper, but if there were a large group of photographs for one subject (such as a particular school), a separate file for photographs was created.
Subgroup 1: General Files (1909-1995)
This material has series named for a subject (i.e. Integration) or type of material (i.e. Publications), and arranged alphabetically by these terms. Files are arranged by individual subjects and sometimes individual items.
Subgroup 2: Individual Schools (1910-2004)
Within Subgroup 2 the records are arranged into series alphabetically by school and then by type of material. Many times items are filed individually, and the file name is the title of that document.
Subgroup 3: Parent-Teacher Associations and Council of PTAs (1916-2004)
In Subgroup 3, individual PTA groups are filed alphabetically by school. Many times items are filed individually, and the file name is the title of that document. After the school-by-school listing is the PTA County Council series, arranged by type of material.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
https://ead.lib.virginia.edu/vivaxtf/view?docId=arlington/ViAr00009.xml RG 9, Records of the Citizen's Committee for School Improvement
Related Material
RG 19, Personal Papers of Elizabeth Pfohl Campbell
Related Material
RG 18, Personal Papers of Barbara Marx
Related Material
RG 70, Personal Papers of Barnard D. Joy
Related Material
RG 163, Records of the Arlington School Board
Related Material
RG 373, Records of Hoffman-Boston High School
Index Terms
Subjects:
Arlington Public Schools (Arlington, Va.); Public schools -- United States.; Segregation in education -- United States.; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- General Files
  - School Board
    - Accomplishments 1948-1950 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, March-April 1953 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, May 1953 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, June 1953 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, July 1953 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, August-November 1953 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, April-July 1954 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, August-December 1954 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, January-February 1955 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, March-June 1955 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Minutes, July-January 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - Agendas and Statements 1964, 1976, 1977, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Applicants 1983 (Box 2)
    - Applicants 1984 (Box 2)
    - Applicants 1985, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Applicant Questionnaires 1988, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Appointments 1960, 1965, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Candidate Conference, Delegates citizens' assoc. 1949 (Box 2)
    - Candidate Conference, Delegates schools 1949 (Box 2)
    - Candidate Conference, Delegates PTA 1949 (Box 2)
    - Candidate Conference, Miscellaneous groups 1949 (Box 2)
    - Committee to uphold the Electorate 1948 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1955, 1966, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Court Cases (Box 2)
    - Election Ephemera 1951-1956 (Box 2)
    - Draheim-Keating campaign canvassing committee 1953 (Box 2)
    - John Locke Green (Box 2)
    - Memorandum 1954 (Box 2)
    - Nominating Convention 1947 (Box 2)
    - Nominating Convention 1949 (Box 2)
    - Nominating Conventions 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Nominating Conventions 1955-1957, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Report 1971-1972, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
    - Speech "Let's Not Abandon Our War Babies," Barnard Joy (Box 2)
    - Summaries of the actions considered and taken by the School Board 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Transportation
    - Architectural report 1964-1971 (Box 3)
    - Architectural Facility Survey 1986 (Box 3)
    - Asbestos removal 1985 (Box 3)
    - Building consolidation 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Building information 1955 (Box 3)
    - Building utilization study 1983 (Box 3)
    - Calculation of capacity of elementary schools 1947-1948 (Box 3)
    - Capital improvement plan 1960 (Box 3)
    - Capital outlays 1947 (Box 3)
    - Consolidation timetable 1983 (Box 3)
    - Consolidation studies 1971-1983 (Box 3)
    - Construction and consolidation 1976 (Box 3)
    - "School Consolidation and Building Utilization Study" 1983 (Box 3)
    - Construction, costs and cost projections (1) 1949-1955 (Box 3)
    - Construction, costs and cost projections (2) 1949-1955 (Box 3)
    - Educational space utilization 1983 (Box 4)
    - Elementary school, crowding report 1988 (Box 4)
    - Elementary school, facilities report 1974 (Box 4)
    - Evaluation study of school site 1972 (Box 4)
    - Four quarter plan of operation of schools 1957 (Box 4)
    - Instructional equipment price lists 1954-1955 (Box 4)
    - Interagency planning operation 1972 (Box 4)
    - Interim reports 1977 (Box 4)
    - Library equipment 1954 (Box 4)
    - Physical education equipment 1954-1955 (Box 4)
    - Redistricting 1977 (Box 4)
    - Report, Arlington County survey 1951 (Box 4)
    - School districts, maps 1975 (Box 4)
    - Schools, capital improvement plan 1989-1994, 1990-1995 (Box 4)
    - School sites 1970 (Box 4)
    - Sidewalk report 1971, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Site survey 1952 (Box 4)
    - Technical education career center 1972 (Box 5)
    - Traffic control at school crossings 1950 (Box 5)
    - Transporation department 1955 (Box 5)
  - Personnel
    - Agreement on Johnson vs. Arlington County School Board 1975 (Box 5)
    - Arlington County, personnel policies 1953, 1955 (Box 5)
    - Census instructions 1948 (Box 5)
    - Census 1968 (Box 5)
    - Census vol. 1 and 2 1968 (Box 5)
    - Census 1983 (Box 5)
    - Certification of school librarians 1955-1956 (Box 5)
    - Citizenship rights of school personnel 1955, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Directory 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Instructional staff allocation report 1975 (Box 5)
    - Pay plans 1987 (Box 5)
    - Pay plan, Allen report 1954 (Box 5)
    - Pay plan, Allen report appendix 1954 (Box 6)
    - Pay plan, Allen report response 1954 (Box 6)
    - Personnel miscellaneous 1950-1955 (Box 6)
    - Personnel news stems 1958, 1959, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Persnnel policies 1951 (Box 6)
    - Personnel policies and procedures 1957 (Box 6)
    - Personnel polices and procedures manual 1958 (Box 6)
    - Principal's Handbook 1952-1953 (Box 6)
    - Principal's Handbook 1953-1954 (Box 6)
    - School board wage survey 1977 (Box 6)
    - Schools contract forms 1940-1959 (Box 6)
    - Schools miscellaneous surveys "Working together: privat and public schools" 1958 (Box 6)
    - Schools, night schools salaries (Box 6)
    - Schools salaries 1952-1954 (Box 6)
    - Study of administrative structure and staffing 1973 (Box 6)
    - Supplemental retirement plan 1953, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Supplemental retirement system portfolio summary 1978, 1979, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Supplemental retirement systems 1979-1980 (Box 7)
    - Supplemental retirement systems, September-November 1980 (Box 7)
    - Survey of non-academic services vol. 1 [1] 1962 (Box 7)
    - Survey of non-academic services vol 1 [2] 1962 (Box 7)
    - Survey of non-acadmeic services vol. 2 1962 (Box 7)
    - Teacher's handbooks 1951-1952, 1952-1953, 1957-1959 (Box 7)
    - Virginia certification regulations 1950 (Box 7)
  - Finances
    - "Arlington County Finances," L. L. Ecker-Racz 1955 (Box 7)
    - Bonds, newsclippings 1951 (Box 7)
    - Bond issue information 1947, 1950-1951 (Box 7)
    - Bond issue flyers 1951-1956 (Box 7)
    - Bond sales 1951-1963 (Box 7)
    - Bond information 1952 (Box 8)
    - Bond information 1953-1956 (Box 8)
    - Bond issue information 1958-1973 (Box 8)
    - Budgets 1934-1935, 1936-1937, 1948-1949, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
    - Budget estimates 1947-1952 (Box 8)
    - Budget estimates 1953-1957 (Box 8)
    - Budgets 1950-1951, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
    - Budgets 1954-1955 (Box 8)
    - Budgets 1955-1956 (Box 8)
    - Budgets, operating 1956-1958 (Box 8)
    - Budgets 1958-1959 (Box 9)
    - Budgets 1962-1963, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - Budget information 1954, 1957, 1966, 1972, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Budget superintendent's presentation 1967 (Box 9)
    - Budget tentative 1976 (Box 9)
    - Budget planning factors 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence concerning finances 1954-1955, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Cost-Ed Analysis [1] 1972 (Box 9)
    - Cost-Ed Analysis [2] 1972 (Box 9)
    - Cost-Ed Analysis [3] 1972 (Box 9)
    - Costs 1950 (Box 9)
    - Debt structure 1950-1951 (Box 9)
    - 1952-1976 (Box 10)
    - 1976-1990 (Box 11)
    - Federal employees' effect on schools 1950 (Box 12)
    - Finances of Arlington County 1955 (Box 12)
    - Financing public schools 1979 (Box 12)
    - Insurance Advisory Committee - School Board Insurance Fund 1954 (Box 12)
    - Records Retention 1969 (Box 12)
    - Report "Arlington County's next decade 1959 (Box 12)
    - School lunch programs 1953-1955 (Box 12)
    - Special education funds 1989 (Box 12)
    - Survey of public schools 1909-1926 (Box 12)
    - Tuition fees 1954 (Box 12)
  - Instruction
    - Academic Performance Reports 1977-1979, 1980-1981, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
    - Accelerated and Enrichment Programs task group 1964-1965 (Box 12)
    - Adult education 1960-1961 (Box 12)
    - Avisory Committee 1951-1957, 1966, 1975 (Box 12)
    - Advisory Committee Reports 1968, 1986-1987 (Box 12)
    - Advisory Councils List 1951-1956, 1971-1975 (Box 12)
    - Alternative Schools, status report 1978-1980 (Box 12)
    - Art Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 12)
    - Arts 1953-1954 (Box 12)
    - Audio-Visual Materials Committee 1948-1950 (Box 12)
    - Calendars 1955-1964 (Box 13)
    - Commission to study secondary schools 1982 (Box 13)
    - Cooperative Training Advisory Council 1955-1956 (Box 13)
    - Critical Thinking and Analytical Skills 1976 (Box 13)
    - Advisory Council on Curriculum 1963 (Box 13)
    - Advisory Council on Curriculum 1964 (Box 13)
    - Advisory Council on Curriculum 1965-1966 (Box 13)
    - Curriculum bulletin 1950-1954 (Box 13)
    - Day Care Program 1974-1975 (Box 13)
    - Developments in Arlington Schools (Box 13)
    - Directory of Program 1974-1975 (Box 13)
    - Educational Excellence (Box 13)
    - Elementary School Study Committee 1973, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Fact Sheet 1984-1985 (Box 13)
    - Task Group on Federal Regulations 1965 (Box 13)
    - Five Year Plan 1975-1979, 1976-1980 (Box 13)
    - Foreign Languages 1954 (Box 13)
    - Grading 1954 (Box 13)
    - Graduation minimum requirements 1977-1978 (Box 13)
    - Guidance Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 13)
    - Guidance Program 1955 (Box 14)
    - Health and Physical Education 1954-1955 (Box 14)
    - Health Advisory Council 1947-1956 (Box 14)
    - Hearing Conservation Class 1955 (Box 14)
    - High School Courses 1954 (Box 14)
    - Higher Education Needs 1977 (Box 14)
    - Higher Edcuation Task Force 1964 (Box 14)
    - Home Economics Advisory Council 1954-1957 (Box 14)
    - Homebound Instruction 1953-1955 (Box 14)
    - Improvement Plan 1978-1980 (Box 14)
    - Individualized Education Program (Box 14)
    - In-Service Education Committee (Box 14)
    - Instruction Advisory Council 1976 (Box 14)
    - Instruction Community Council 1951-1956 (Box 14)
    - Instructional Program Resources/Results 1980 (Box 14)
    - Citizens' Committee on Allocation of Instructional Resources 1975 (Box 14)
    - Division of Instruction 1950-1954 (Box 14)
    - Division of Instruction Report 1966-1967, 1975 (Box 14)
    - Junior High School 1955 (Box 14)
    - Junior H. S. Program Task Group 1963 (Box 14)
    - Kindergarten Advisory Council 1952-1956 (Box 14)
    - Kindergartens 1948-1955 (Box 14)
    - Libraries Department 1954-1955 (Box 14)
    - Library Advisory Council 1953-1956 (Box 14)
    - Mathematics 1953-1955 (Box 14)
    - Music 1953-1954 (Box 14)
    - Music Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 14)
    - Orientation Handbooks for non-native speakers of English (Box 14)
    - Parent Attitudinal Survey Report 1980 (Box 14)
    - Personnel Policies Council 1954 (Box 15)
    - Physical Education Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 15)
    - Pre-Primary 1955 (Box 15)
    - Principals 1953-1954 (Box 15)
    - Reading 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Reading is Fundamental 1977 (Box 15)
    - Report Cards 1950-1951 (Box 15)
    - Reporting System 1953, 1954, 1958, 1970 (Box 15)
    - School Lunch Advisory Council 1947-1956 (Box 15)
    - Science 1955 (Box 15)
    - Special Education Advisory Council 1953, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Special Education Handbooks 1975, 1979-1980, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Special Education Policies and Procedures 1982 (Box 15)
    - Special Services Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 15)
    - Speech Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 15)
    - Speech Education 1954-1955 (Box 15)
    - Staff Meetings 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Standardized Test Results Summary 1972-1976 (Box 15)
    - Summer School, Elementary and Secondary 1961, 1987-1988 (Box 15)
    - Teaching Materials Advisory Council 1955-1956 (Box 15)
    - Teaching Materials Center 1948-1954 (Box 15)
    - Testing Program 1953 (Box 15)
    - Textbooks, Task Group on Elementary 1964 (Box 15)
    - Textbooks, 1951-1955 19 (Box 15)
    - Trades and Industry Advisory Council 1954-1956 (Box 15)
  - Students
    - Alcohol, Drug and Tobacco Survey 1981 (Box 15)
    - Attendance Task Group 1974 (Box 15)
    - Black Achievement and Participation 1987 (Box 15)
    - Census of Students 1950, 1953 (Box 15)
    - Continuing Education Needs vol. 1 and 2 1979, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Disabled; Learning Disabilities 1977 (Box 16)
    - Drop Out Study 1962-1963 (Box 16)
    - Drugs 1977 (Box 16)
    - Educational Responsibilities and Rights 1971 (Box 16)
    - Elementary School Attendance 1966-1967 (Box 16)
    - Enrollment Committee Report 1974 (Box 16)
    - Enrollment Projections 1976-1977 (Box 16)
    - Ethnic Student Achievement 1986 (Box 16)
    - Exceptional Children Coordination (Box 16)
    - Field Trips 1977 (Box 16)
    - Gifted Children 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 16)
    - Guide for Parochial School Health Program 1961 (Box 16)
    - Handicapped 1953-1955, 1975 (Box 16)
    - Limited English Proficiency 1977-1981 (Box 16)
    - Mathews vs. School Board 1955 (Box 16)
    - Mentally Retarded 1954, 1958 (Box 16)
    - Research Division, student studies 1952-1958 (Box 16)
    - Responsible Student Conduct 1978 (Box 16)
    - Suspension Report 1982-1985 (Box 16)
  - Junior High/Middle School
    - Middle Schools 1975 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous 1952-1965 (Box 16)
    - Secondary Reorganization 1979 (Box 16)
    - School Board Jr. High Consolidation 1977 (Box 17)
  - Integration
    - Texts of Supreme Court Segregation Ruling 1954 (Box 17)
    - Civil Action no. 331 1954 (Box 17)
    - Desegregation Plans in Arlington 1954-1955, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Committee to Preserve Public Schools 1958-1959 (Box 17)
    - Committee to Study Problems of Integration in the Arlington Schools, Minutes 1954-1955 (Box 17)
    - "Facts Concerning Segregation and Integration" 1954 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence and Publications 1954-1958 (Box 17)
    - "A First Step Towards School Integration" 1958 (Box 17)
    - Wanner vs. Arlington County School Board, decision 1966 (Box 17)
    - "Virginia's Massive Resistance" by Joan Roberts 1965 (Box 17)
    - Desegregation Issues 1986 (Box 17)
    - Desegregation Decisions 1987 (Box 17)
    - Clippings about Arlington Integration [1] 1959-1961 (Box 17)
    - Clippings about Arlington Integration [2] 1959-1961 (Box 17)
    - Clippings about Arlington Integration [3] 1959-1961 (Box 17)
    - Clippings about Stratford Jr. H. S. 1951-1960, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence with Claude Richmond 1959 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence with Claude Richmond (photocopies) 1959 (Box 18)
    - Anti-integration 1958-1959 (Box 18)
    - Photograph of Claude Richmond (Box 18)
    - Doris Matthews, "Stratford: Virginia's First Integrated School" 1991 (Box 18)
  - Publications
    - Abstract: Study of the Public Schools of Arlington Co. 1941 (Box 18)
    - Arlington Know How Bulletin 1951-1953 (Box 18)
    - "Arlington Public Schools" 1975 (Box 18)
    - Arlington School News 1952-1965 (Box 18)
    - Arlington Schools in Action 1966-1967 (Box 18)
    - Arlington Schools, Their Conditions and Needs, Fall 1966 (Box 18)
    - Basic information guide, Washington Board of Ed. 1977-1978 (Box 18)
    - Calendar 1948 (Box 18)
    - Clippings 1950-1984 (Box 18)
    - Concert Programs 1950-1955 (Box 18)
    - Evaluation of the Guidance Program 1966 (Box 18)
    - Filed Trip Directory 1951 (Box 18)
    - Film "The Fight for Better Schools" 1950 (Box 18)
    - Focus 1967 (Box 18)
    - Guide to secondary school programs 1977-1978 (Box 18)
    - Handbook for Parents and Students [1] 1952-1958 (Box 18)
    - Handbook for Parents and Students [2] 1952-1958 (Box 18)
    - Handbook for Parents and Students (Spanish) 1979 (Box 19)
    - Handbook for Parents and Students 1980/1989 (Box 19)
    - History 1973-1974 (Box 19)
    - "Know Your School Fact Sheet" no. 1-4 1963 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous 1951-1963 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous [1] 1971-1978 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous [2] 1971-1978 (Box 19)
    - "News from the Arlington County Public Schools" 1965 (Box 19)
    - "News from Arlington Educators" 1965-1966 (Box 19)
    - Newsletter costs 1954 (Box 19)
    - Public Education in the Northern Virginia area 1956 (Box 19)
    - "School Reporter" 1975-1978 (Box 19)
    - Status report to School Board Supt. 1976-1977 (Box 19)
    - Superintendent's Bulletins 1940-1951 (Box 19)
    - Superintendent's annual plan 1976-1980 (Box 19)
    - Superintendent's Annual Reports 1953-1984 (Box 19)
    - Surveys 1927, 1930 (Box 20)
    - Teacher Salary Survey 1951-1957 (Box 20)
    - Telephone Directories 1976-1977 (Box 20)
    - Tenure Publications 1942-1944 (Box 20)
    - Virginia Bulletin 1955 (Box 20)
    - Arlington County Civic Federation 1946-1951 (Box 20)
    - Various Groups interested in schools 1950-1962 (Box 20)
- Individual Schools
  - Abingdon
    - Groundbreaking Ceremonies 1949 (Box 20)
  - Barcroft
    - Architectural Program 1972 (Box 20)
  - Barrett
    - Architectural Engineering study, May 1972 (Box 20)
  - Brandon
    - School site 1954-1955 (Box 20)
  - Cherrydale
    - Alternative uses of school site (Box 20)
    - History (Box 20)
    - Neighborhood analysis, November 1972 (Box 20)
  - Claremont
    - Accreditation Certificate 1978 (Box 20)
    - Code of Behavior (Box 20)
    - Correspondence 1963, 1974 (Box 20)
    - Handbook 1968-1969 (Box 20)
    - Newsclippings 1950-1979 (Box 20)
    - Photographs (general) 1956-1979 (Box 20)
    - Poetry Project 1978 (Box 20)
    - Programs 1966, 1970 (Box 20)
    - Staff Lists 1952-1963 (Box 20)
    - Student Newspapers 1956-1974 (Box 20)
    - School Pictures 1958-1980 (Box 20)
    - School Pictures 1980-1981, 1982-1983 (Box 21)
  - Drew
    - Opening Program (Box 21)
  - Edison
    - Article 1963 (Box 21)
  - Fairlington
    - Classbooks 1971/1972, 1972/1973, 1976/1977 (Box 21)